Register of the Pasternak Family Papers, 1877-2012
Hoover Institution Archives
- PASTERNAK TRUST ARCHIVES, 1877-2012; 118.0 boxes
  - BORIS PASTERNAK FILE, 1914-2013
    - Writings about Boris Pasternak, critical reviews and biographical materials, 1956-2010 (Box-folder 147: 5-9)
      - Barnes, Christopher, 1983 and undated (Box-folder 147: 6)
        - "Poeziia i muzyka. Vtoraia stikhiia Borisa Pasternaka," Russkaia mysl', nos. 3455 and 3456, with cover letter to Lydia Pasternak Slater. Photocopy, 1983 March
      - Berg, Robert von, "Pasternak Poesie ist Musik." Typescript, undated (Box-folder 147: 7)
      - Boden, "Boris Pasternak: On Reading Doctor Zhivago." Typescript, 1958
      - Bozen, Sender, "Boris Pasternak: Geletbrief - Entwurf zu einem Selbstbildnis." Typescript, photocopy, 1986
      - Bräuer, Herbert, "Pasternak's Bedetung als Dichter," Alma Mater Philippina, Marburger Universitätsbund E.V., 1958
      - Chiarmonte, Nicola, 1958-1959
        - "Pasternak's Message," Partisan Review, pp. 127-134. Reprint, 1958 Winter
        - "Doktor Zhivago and Modern Sensibility," Dissent, pp. 35-44. Reprint, 1959 Winter
      - Dahl, Jelena, "Nekotorye osobennosti zvukovykh povtorov Borisa Pasternaka," Institutum Slavicum Universitatis Gothoburgensis. Bound typescript, 1978 (Box-folder 147: 8)
      - Döning, Johanna Renate, untitled typescript, 1968 (Box-folder 147: 9)
      - Fleishman, Lazar, "Iz perepiski Pasternaka," unidentified publication. Photocopy, undated
      - Frank, Margot K., "Letters: Summer, 1926," MAGILL's Literary Annual, 1956
      - Frank, Victor, "Boris Pasternak," presentation at the conference on Soviet literature, 1917-1962. Typescript
      - Fricke, Peter, untitled typescript, undated
      - Gladkov, Aleksandr, "Zima v Chistopole. Vospominaniia o B. L. Pasternake," Literaturnoe obozrenie, no. 4, pp. 103-111. Photocopy, 1978 (Box-folder 148: 1)
      - Gorelov, Pavel, "Razmyshleniia nad romanom," Voprosy Literatury, no. 10, 1988
      - 1958 November (Box-folder 148: 1)
      - Humboldt, Charles, "The Case of Doctor Zhivago," Mainstream, pp. 1-23, 1958 November
      - Ingold, Felix, "Beschedenheit und Kühnheit," Studio Basel broadcast transcript, 1965
      - Ivinskaia, Ol'ga. "Mein Leben mit Pasternak," Zeit Magazin, nos. 34/18 (pp. 4-8) and 35/25 (pp. 10, 12, and 16), 1978
      - Katkov, George. "Bezliub'e" - rannii nabrosok Doktora Zhivago, presentation at the Colloque de Cerisy-la Salle. Published excerpt, 1975 (Box-folder 148: 2)
      - Kaverin, Veniamin. "Proza Pasternaka," Knizhnoe obozrenie, undated
      - Levertov, Denise. "Pasternak in English," Jubilee, pp. 41-44, 1962 June
      - Mallac, Guy de, 1963, 1973
        - "Boris Pasternak: A Chronology" (sketch for a biography), with Michael Heim Berman, 1963
        - "Pasternak and Religion," reprint from the Russian Review, vol. 32, no. 4, 1973 October
        - "Pasternak's Critical-Esthetic Views," Russian Literature Triquarterly, no. 6, 1973 Spring
      - Matzov, Anna," The Individual and Time in the Structure of Pasternak's Novel Doctor Zhivago," PhD thesis, School of Graduate Studies of the University of Ottawa, 1983 (Box-folder 148: 3-5)
      - Merton, Thomas, "The Pasternak Affair in Perspective," reprint from THOUGHT, Fordham University Quarterly, vol, 34, no. 135, 1959-1960 Winter (Box-folder 148: 6)
      - Monas, Sidney, "A Miracle Is a Miracle," The Hudson Review, 1958-1959 Winter (Box-folder 148: 6)
      - Nivat, George, 1974, 1987
        - "Six lettres inédites de Boris Pasternak," Cahiers du Monde russe et sovétique. XV (1-2), p. 220-233. Photocopy, 1974 January-June
        - "Que La vie est généreuse envers moi!" Journal de Genève, photocopy, with cover letter from Alfonse Aeby, 1987 August
      - Obolenskii, Dmitrii, "Poeziia B. L. Pasternaka." Typescript, undated
      - Pappenheim, Mark, "A difference of Sympathies, Perhaps?" Typescript, circa 1988 (Box-folder 148: 7)
      - Pasternak, Evgenii, undated (Box-folder 148: 7)
        - "Perepiska Borisa Pasternaka," with Elliott Mossman (in Russian and English). Typescript (photocopy), undated
        - "Reading Pasternak - Some Errors Corrected," transcript. Translations and notes by Christopher Barnes, undated
      - Poggioli, Renato, "Boris Pasternak," Partisan Review, 1958 Fall (Box-folder 148: 8)
      - Reëm, Ido, "Nightmare of a Poet" (in English and Hebrew). Typescript, 1961
      - Schimanski Stefan, "Boris Pasternak: The Lonely Sail." Typescript, undated
      - Schweitzer, Renate, "Danksagung an Boris Pasternak," typescript, undated (Box-folder 148: 9-10)
      - Shmeman, Alexander, "Pasternak Died," Radio Liberty special broadcast. Transcript, 1960 (Box-folder 149: 1)
      - Silbajoris, Rimvydas, 1965, 1967 (Box-folder 149: 1)
        - "Poetic Texture of Doctor Živago," The Slavic and East European Journal (reprint), vol. IX, no. 1, 1965
        - "Pasternak and Tolstoj: Some Comparisons," The Slavic and East European Journal, vol. XI, no. 1, 1967 Spring
      - Siniavskiĭ, Andreĭ, "Odin den' s Pasternakon," photocopy from unidentified periodical, undated
      - Stora, Judith, "Pasternak et le Judaïsme," Cahiers du Monde russe et sovétique, vol. IX, no. 3-4, 1968
      - Storck, Joachim W., "Bertrage und Materialen zu Marina Cvetaeva, Boris Pasternak, Il'ja Érenburg, Osip Mandel'štam," typescript (photocopy), undated
      - Struve, Gleb, "Sense and Nonsense about Doctor Zhivago, Studies in Russian and Polish Literature" (reprint), pp. 229-250, 1962
      - Voznesenskiĭ, Andreĭ, 1980 and undated (Box-folder 149: 2)
        - "Mne chetyrnadtsat' let..., " Novyi mir (photocopy), no. 9, 1980
        - "Nebo Borisa Pasternaka," photocopy from unidentified periodical, undated
      - Williams, Allan Moray, 1974; 1987 and undated
        - "Nur far de deres Pasternak tilbage," clipping from Danish newspaper with English translation, undated
        - "Sovjetisk Hyldest til Pasternaks Hamlet-oversættelse," clipping from Danish newspaper (photocopy), circa 1987
        - "Voice from the Grave: New Poems by Pasternak Published." Typescript, undated
        - "Pasternak's Mistress Has Written a Book about Him," typescript (photocopy), undated
      - Zaitsev, Boris, "Vechnost'," Slovo (photocopy ), no. 2, pp. 49-51, 1990
      - Unidentified authors, 1958, 1984 (Box-folder 149: 3)
        - "Boris Pasternak- nonconformist Russian," Book-of-the-Month Club News, pp. 9, 16 (reprint from New York Tmes), 1958 December
        - "Pravda Denounces Pasternak and the Nobel Award," Current Digest of Soviet Press: The Joint Committee on Slavic Studies, vol. X, no. 39, pp. 6-7, 1958
        - " Novyi Mir Editor's Letter Rejecting Doctor Zhivago," Current Digest of Soviet Press: The Joint Committee on Slavic Studies, vol. X, no. 43, pp. 3-6, 1958
        - "Two Writers in Soviet Society: Fadeyev and Pasternak." Typescript, 1984
    - Writings by others, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 149: 4-6)
      Includes writings by Olga Carlisle, Max Hayward, Paul Casimir, Calvin Brown, Kurt Wolff, Ido Reem, Renate Schweitzer, and others and poems devoted to Boris Pasternak.
    - Photographs, undated (Box-folder 149: 7)
    - Printed matter, 1962-1986 (Box-folder 149: 8-9)
    - Clippings, 1922-2013 and undated (Oversize-box 171-173)
      - 1922-1976 (Oversize-box 172)
      - 1939-1945 (Oversize-box 171)
      - 1977-2013 and undated (Oversize-box 173)
  - ALEKSANDR PASTERNAK FILE, 1927-2004
    - Writings, 1975-1987 and undated
      - "Dalekoe blizkoe: Detstvo i molodost' sem'i," vospominaniia. Typescript, 1975 (Box-folder 150: 1-6)
      - "A Vanished Present," memoirs. Typescript and uncorrected proof, 1983 (Box-folder 150: 7-11; 151: 1-5)
        - Typescript, circa 1983 (Box-folder 150: 7-11; 151: 1)
        - Introduction, draft, circa 1983 (Box-folder 151: 2)
        - Uncorrected proofs, 1983 (Box-folder 151: 3-4)
        - Working papers, undated (Box-folder 151: 5)
      - Miscellanea, undated (Box-folder 150: 6)
        Includes publications in periodicals and broadcast of Aleksandr Pasternak's memoirs.
    - Printed matter relating to architecture, 1927-2004 (Box-folder 150: 7-8)
      Includes photographs of buildings in Moscow.
  - JOSEPHINE PASTERNAK FILE, 1920s-1987
    - Correspondence, circa1920s-1986
      - General, 1927-1987
        - Adelson, Abram and Stella., 1936; 1962-1981 and undated (Box-folder 152: 1-4)
          - 1936, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 152: 1)
          - 1969-1969 (Box-folder 152: 2)
          - 1970-1973 (Box-folder 152: 3)
          - 1974-1981 and undated (Box-folder 152: 4)
        - Aeby, Alphonse, 1975-1987 (Box-folder 152: 5)
        - Barwise, Lily, 1985
        - Bell, Jennisen, 1969
        - Blair, Kitty H., 1957
        - Breitman, Mikhail, 1960
        - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1948-1958
        - Buckman, David, 1974
        - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1979; 1982 (Box-folder 152: 6)
        - D'iakvskaia, Tamara, 1963
        - Dr. Lukas Lichtbild, 1963
        - Éditions du Seuil, 1965
        - Fleishman, Lazar, 1977
        - Freidenberg, Ol'ga, 1927
          Includes Josephine's draft letter.
        - Gagarina, Katia, undated
        - Graphicum, 1962-1976 and undated
          Includes Lydia's draft letter.
        - Hauser, Olga, 1974-1975
        - Hoch, Max, 1977
        - Holzinger, Hans, 1962
        - Hossiason, Philippe and Olga, 1972
        - Kane, Ida, 1983
        - Kollerman-Kolman, G., undated
        - Kovarskaia, B., 1945 (Box-folder 152: 7)
        - Laffitte, Sophie, 1960
        - Lee, Erna, undated
        - Lexicon of Jewish Artists, 1945
        - Librairie Hachette, 1959-1961
        - Lindsay Drummond Ltd., 1943-1948 (Box-folder 152: 7)
        - Liu, B. L., 1981 (Box-folder 152: 8)
        - Lvoff, Vera, 1978
        - MacKinnon, John, 1988
        - Mallac Sauzier, Guy de, 1963-1979
        - Mansback, F., 1960
        - Museum of Modern Art, Oxford, 1983
        - Newburg, A., 1975
        - Odham Press, Ltd., 1943
        - Philipp, Walter, undated
        - Rosenfeld, Ernst, 1937-1963
        - S. Fischer Verlag, 1963 (Box-folder 152: 9)
        - Saderman, Anatol, 1974
        - Salewski, Dagmar, 1975
        - Schmorell, E., 1958
        - Schimanski, Stefan (see also: Lindsay Drummond Ltd.), 1943-1947
          Includes Josephine's draft letters.
        - Simon and Schuster, 1966 (Box-folder 153: 1)
        - Sotheby's, 1981
        - Soviet Union, Torgovaia Delegatsiia (Great Britain), 1943
        - Spat, Judith, 1967, 1982
        - Störig, Hans Joachim, 1962
        - Struve, Gleb, 1945
        - Struve, Nikita, undated.
          A holograph copy of Josephine's letter to Nikita Struve.
        - Swet, Gershon, 1963
        - Sztein, Emanuel, 1985
        - Talbot, Michael, 1945
        - Thames and Hudson Ltd., 1982
        - Time and Tide, weekly review, 1945
        - William, Alan Moray, 1978 (Box-folder 153: 2)
        - Weinberg, Simon, 1963
        - Ugrimoff (Ougrimoff), Nadezhda. Includes a card from Josephine Pasternak, 1939
        - University of Pittsburg, 1959
        - Zaguskin, Jakob (Yakov), undated
        - Unidentified, 1928-1963 and undated
      - Family correspondence, 1921-1986 and undated
        - General, miscellaneous letters and cards from Lydia Slater's children and grandchildren, undated (Box-folder 153: 3)
        - Pasternak, Aleksandr and Irina Vilyam, 1921-1971 (Box-folder 153: 4)
        - Pasternak, Evgenii Borisovich and Elena Vladimirovna, 1961-1986 and undated (Box-folder 153: 5)
        - Pasternak, Fedor (Friedrich), 1939 (Box-folder 153: 6)
        - Pasternak, Leonid Osipovich and Rosalia Isidorovna, 1920s-1939 (Box-folder 153: 7-10)
          - 1920s, 1926 (Box-folder 153: 7)
          - 1927-1929 (Box-folder 153: 8)
          - 1930s, 1932 (Box-folder 153: 9)
          - 1933-1939 (Box-folder 153: 10)
        - Pasternak, Zinaida, 1966 and undated (Box-folder 154: 9)
        - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1920s, 1924-1986 and undated (Box-folder 153: 11-12; 154: 1-8)
          - 1920s (Box-folder 153: 11)
          - 1924-1925 (Box-folder 153: 12)
          - 1926-1927 (Box-folder 154: 1)
          - 1928-1929 (Box-folder 154: 2)
          - 1930-1934 (Box-folder 154: 3)
          - 1935 (Box-folder 154: 4)
          - 1936 (Box-folder 154: 5)
          - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 154: 6)
          - 1950s, 1959 (Box-folder 154: 7)
          - 1960-1986 (Box-folder 154: 8)
        - Notes and draft letters, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 154: 10)
    - Writings, 1964-1981 and undated (Box-folder 154: 11-12)
  - OLGA FREIDENBERG FILE, circa 1900s-1991 (Box 155-159)
    - Correspondence, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 155: 1-3)
    - Writings, 1900s-1950
      - Memoirs, holograph and typescript, 1900s-1950 (Box-folder 155: 4-9; 159: 1-7, Box 156-158)
        - Holograph, 1900s-1950 (Box-folder 155: 4-9; 156: 1-10; 157: 1-6)
          - Books 1-2, circa 1900-1917 (Box-folder 155: 4)
          - Books 3-4, circa 1917-1920 (Box-folder 155: 5)
          - Book 5, 1921-1924 (Box-folder 155: 6)
          - Book 6, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 155: 7)
          - Book 7, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 155: 8)
          - Book 8, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 155: 9)
          - Book 9, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 156: 1)
          - Book 10, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 156: 2)
          - Book 11, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 156: 3)
          - Books 12-20, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 156: 4-9)
            Notebooks entitled "Osada cheloveka" relate to the siege of Leningrad.
          - Books 21-22, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 156: 10)
          - Books 23-24, 1945-1946 (Box 157: 1)
          - Books 25-26, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 157: 2)
          - Books 27-28, 1947 (Box-folder 157: 3)
          - Books 29-32, 1948 (Box-folder 157: 4-5)
          - Books 33-34, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 157: 6)
        - Typescript, 1900s-1950 (Box-folder 157: 7-11; 158: 1-12; 159: 1-7)
        - Excerpts from memoirs. Typescript (photocopy), 1941 (Box-folder 159: 8)
      - Scholarly writings, 1930-1941 (Box-folder 159: 9)
    - Writings about Olga Freidenberg, 1988-1991 and undated (Box-folder 159: 10)
  - EVGENII PASTERNAK WRITINGS, 1977, 1989, 1991 and undated (Box-folder 160: 1-10; 161: 1-5)
    - "Boris Pasternak: Kniga ob ottse." Galley (photocopy), circa 1989 (Box-folder 160: 1-10)
    - "Boris Pasternak: Khronologiia zhizni i tvorchestva,", undated (Box-folder 161: 1)
    - "Korrektura oshibok pri chtenii Borisa Pasternaka." Typescript, 1977
      Includes letter from Bengt Jangfeldt.
    - Lectures about Boris Pasternak (1-9), undated (Box-folder 161: 2-3)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 161: 4)
    - Untitled poem, undated
    - Scholarly writings, 1977 (Box-folder 161: 5)
  - MICHAEL SLATER FILE, 1928-1999 and undated (Box-folder 161: 6-13)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1999 and undated (Box-folder 161: 6-10)
      - General, 1960-1999 (Box-folder 161: 6-9)
        - Casual Club, 1989 (Box-folder 161: 6)
        - Constantine Air Services, Ltd., 1972 (Box-folder 161: 7)
        - Fleishman, Lazar, 1986-1987
          Includes letters from Michael Slater to Lazar Fleishman and letters from Juda Magnum Museum.
        - Loudmer, Guy, 1971-1972
        - Packer, Vera, undated
        - Salys, Rimgaila, 1983-1999 (Box-folder 161: 7-8)
        - Zaguskin, Jacob (Yakov), 1960 (Box-folder 161: 9)
        - Unidentified, undated
      - Family, circa 1962-1991 (Box-folder 161: 10)
        - Pasternak, Evgenii B., 1984-1991
        - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1962-1965; 1984
        - Slater, Nicolas Pasternak, 1960s
    - Subject file, 1928-1987 (Box-folder 161: 11-13; 162: 1-12)
      - EP group of Companies, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 161: 11)
        Includes Sussex Tapes catalogs
      - Exhibit materials, 1928-1987 and undated (Box-folder 161: 12-13)
        Includes catalogs and flyers.
      - Jewish Museum, 1988-1989 and undated (Box-folder 162: 1)
      - Maltazan Gallery, Ltd., 1974-1976 (Box-folder 162: 2)
      - Pasternak Trust materials, 1980-1987 (Box-folder 162: 3-4)
      - Rheims, Philippe, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 162: 5)
        ncludes correspondence, with related letters from Judith Spat, and Lydia Pasternak's draft letters.
      - Smithsonian Institution Travelling Exhibition Service, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 162: 6-12, Box-folder 163: 1-4)
        Includes correspondence, legal documents, condition reports, captions, and Leonid Pasternak biographical data,
      - State Tret'yakov Gallery, 1977-1979, 1982 and undated (Box-folder 163: 5-7)
  - NICOLAS PASTERNAK SLATER FILE, 1951-circa 1990s (Box-folder 163: 8-13; 164: 1-4)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1981 (Box-folder 163: 8)
      - General, greeting cards and telegrams, 1951
      - Adelson, Abram and Stella (letter from Nicolas Pasternak Slater and Maya Slater), undated
      - Harkevitch, Nina, 1963
      - Pasternak, Aleksandr, 1965
      - Pasternak, Anna (daughter of Aleksandr Pasternak), undated
      - Pasternak, Evgenii Borisovich, 1971-1981
      - Pasternak, Leonid Borisovich, undated
      - Ross (draft letters from Nicolas and Lydia Pasternak Slater), undated
      - Saderman, Anatol, 1963 (Box-folder 163: 9)
      - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1951, 1965
      - Wulff, Kurt (from Nicolas Pasternak Slater), 1961
    - Writings, 1990s and undated (Box-folder 163: 10-13; 164: 1-4)
      - "Perepiska s roditeliami i sestrami." Typescript (photocopy), 1990s (Box-folder 163: 10-13; 164: 1-3)
      - Translation samples, undated (Box-folder 164: 4)
  - ANN PASTERNAK SLATER CORRESPONDENCE, 1959-2009 (Box-folder 164: 7-11)
    - General, 1967-2009 (Box-folder 164: 5-6)
      - Averbukh, Sergey (Serge), 1994 and undated (Box-folder 164: 5)
      - Barnes, Christopher, 1985 and undated
      - Balfour, Gwen, 1972
      - Chernykh, Olga, 1991-1992 and undated
      - Demurova, Nina, 1991
      - Fudge and Co., Ltd., 1971
      - Harkevitch, Nina, 1967-1968
      - Hossiason, Philippe and Olga, 1977, 1991
      - Hughes, Olga, 1982
      - Livingstone, Angela, 2009
      - Oxford University Press, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 164: 6)
      - Packer, Vera, undated
      - Philipp, Walter, undated
      - S. Fischer Verlag, 1987
      - Salys, Rimgaila (Rima), 1995
        Includes her translations of Boris Pasternak letters.
      - Sanson, Josh, 1975
      - Schapiro, Efim, 1969
      - Sill, David, 1992
      - Unidentified, undated
        Includes translation of Boris Pasternak's letters.
    - Family letters, 1959-1994 (Box-folder 164: 7-11)
      - Pasternak, Aleksandr, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 164: 7)
      - Pasternak, Aleksandr and Irina Vilyam, 1970-1985 (Box-folder 164: 8)
      - Pasternak (Oppenheimer), Catherine (Rosa), 1964, 1970 (Box-folder 164: 9)
      - Pasternak, Evgenii Borisovich, 1975-1993
      - Pasternak, Fedor (son of Aleksandr Pasternak) and Rosa (his wife), 1991 (Box-folder 164: 10)
      - Pasternak, Josephine, 1963-1968 and undated
      - Pasternak, Maria, undated
      - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1959-1968
      - Slater, Nicolas Pasternak and Maya Slater, undated
      - Vilyam, Anna Nikolaevna (sister of Irina Vilyam), 1990-1994 (Box-folder 164: 11)
      - Unidentified, 1988
  - CATHERINE SLATER CORRESPONDENCE, 1948, 1968 and undated (Box-folder 164: 12)
  - HELEN AND KURT WOLFF FILE, 1929-1971 (Box 165; 174-176)
    - Boris Pasternak file, 1958-1960 and undated (Box-folder 165: 1-2)
      - Correspondence, 1958-1960 and undated (Box-folder 165: 1-2)
        - About Boris Pasternak, 1958-1959 and undated (Box-folder 165: 1)
        - By Boris Pasternak, 1958-1960 and undated (Box-folder 165: 2)
          Includes copies and translations of his letters and excerpts from his letters.
    - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 165: 3-6)
      - Baker, Kate, 1960 (Box-folder 165: 3)
      - Bartlett, Lynn, 1958
      - Becker, 1960
      - Cliburn, Van, 1958
      - Colophon, Curtis, 1959
      - Haber, 1958
      - Hearst Corporation, 1959
      - Hemingway, Ernest, 1959
      - Howe, 1959
      - Jakobson, Roman, 1958
      - Kennedy, Charles, 1958
      - Levin, Harry, 1959
      - Pasternak, Josephine, 1961
      - Pasternak, Zinaida, 1960 (Box-folder 165: 6)
      - Rogers, Miriam, 1959
      - Ruge, Gerd, 1958-1959
      - Salisbury, Harrison, 1959
      - Slater, Lydia Pasternak, 1959-1961 and undated (Box-folder 165: 4)
      - Slater, Nicolas Pasternak, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 165: 5)
        Includes Nicolas Pasternak Slater's translation into English of some letters of Boris Pasternak.
      - Unidentified, 1959-1960
    - Publishing materials, 1958-1959 and undated. (Box-folder 165: 7)
      Includes memoranda, minutes, notices, letters, and other documents.
    - Writings, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 165: 8-10)
      - "Kurt Wolff und Boris Pasternak," typescript for Norddeutscher Rundfunk broadcast, 1962 (Box-folder 165: 8)
      - "Boris Pasternak und Deutschland," typescript for Norddeutscher Rundfunk broadcast, circa 1962 (Box-folder 165: 9)
      - Kurt Wolff: Autoren/Bücher/Abenteuer, after 1963 (Box-folder 165: 10)
    - Clippings, 1929-1971 (Oversize-box 174-176)
      - Relating to the publication of Doctor Zhivago and Nobel Prize affair, 1957-1959 (Oversize-box 174-176)
        Clippings from and photocopies of publications in German, French, Dutch, American, Italian, Russian, and other periodicals.
      - Relating to the death and funeral of Boris Pasternak and arrest of Olga Ivinskaia, 1960-1961 (Oversize-box 175-176)
      - Reviews of Boris Pasternak writings and translations, 1929-1952, 1960-1971 (Oversize-box 176)
  - RARE AND SIGNED BOOK FILE, 1922-1970 and undated (Box 166-167)
  - AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL, 1910-2011 (Box 177-178)
    - Sound recordings, 1958-2010 and undated (Boxes 177-178)
      - 12 vecherov s Pasternakom, 1 sound disc (CD), 2010 (Box 177)
      - "After the Blizzard," BBC program about Boris Pasternak, 1 sound tape reel, 2000 (Box 178)
      - "At the Grave of Boris Pasternak," interview with custodians, 1 sound tape reel, 1978 (Box 178)
      - "Auf was es ankonnt," 1 sound tape reel, undated (Box 178)
      - Boris Pasternak Interview, British Broadcasting Corporation, 3 sound lacquer discs, 1960 (Box 178)
      - Boris Pasternak: Poems, Translated and read by his sister Lydia Pasternak Slater. 2 sound discs (45 rpm), circa 1960 (Box 177)
      - Boris Pasternak: Polnoe sobranie zvukozapisei avtorskogo chteniia, 1 sound disc (CD), 2002 (Box 177)
      - "Boris Pasternak Speaks," 1 sound tape reel, 1958 (Box 178)
      - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation (CBC) program about Boris Pasternak, 2 sound tape reels, 1990 (Box 178)
      - "Christopher Barnes and Aleksandr Pasternak in Conversation," 1 sound tape reel, 1980 (Box 178)
      - "Evening," 1 sound disc (CD), 2008 (Box 177)
      - Igraet Heinrich Neuhaus, 2 sound vinyl discs (33.5 rpm), 1949
      - Igraet A. Skriabin, 1 sound disc (33 rpm), 1910 (Box 177)
      - In Memoriam: Leonie Gombrich, 1 sound disc (45 rpm), undated (Box 177)
      - Interview of Aleksandr Pasternak by CBC, 1 sound tape reel, circa 1980 (Box 178)
      - Lydia Pasternak Slater and Evgeniĭ Pasternak reading Boris Pasternak poetry, 1 sound tape reel, undated (Box 177)
      - "Lydia Pasternak: Writings for Vienna," 1 sound disc (CD), undated (Box 177)
      - "Pasternak," 1 sound tape reel, undated (Box 178)
      - "Pasternak," 2 sound tape reels, undated (Box 178)
      - "Pasternak BBC Broadcast," 2 sound tape reels, 1986 (Box 178)
      - "Pasternak i muzyka," 1 sound tape reel, undated (Box 178)
      - "Pasternak Poetry," 2 sound tape reels, 1983 (Box 177)
      - Pasternak/Skriabin/Prokofjew/Polo de Haas, 1 sound disc (CD), 1993 (Box 178)
      - Pasternak Speaks, 1 sound disc (45 rpm), 1958 (Box 177)
      - "Pasternak-Skriabin-Prokofjew," played by Polo de Haas, 1 sound tape reel, undated (Box 178)